thebalm.com 2019-02-26

# Privacy Policy – theBalm

**Last Updated and Effective as of: May 25, 2018**

At theBalm Cosmetics (“we”, “us” or “theBalm”), we are committed to safeguarding your privacy and protecting your information against unauthorized use. The following statements explain the policies we adhere to regarding the collection of data on our site <https://thebalm.com/> (“Web site”), information security, and privacy standards. This privacy policy does not apply to any other website including social media outlets such as Instagram, Facebook, or Twitter, which we use for business purposes. theBalm is the data controller for data collected on our Web site only. BY USING OR ACCESSING THE WEB SITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR AGREEMENT TO BE BOUND BY TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE WEB SITE.

**Personal Information:**

Your provision of your Personal Information to us is completely voluntary. “Personal Information” is information that can specifically identify you.  We do not collect Personal Information unless you submit that information to us, such as when you choose to participate in our offers and programs or otherwise provide information directly to us, including when you register with us, purchase products, participate in our interactive features or otherwise interact with us on the Web site. Categories of Personal Information we collect include:

  * _Identity Data,_ which includes name or other similar identifiers.
  * _Contact Data,_ which includes address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * _Financial Data,_ which includes payment card details.

Additionally, we may also collect certain other types of information that, along with Identity Data Contact Data, and Financial Data may be considered and specifically named “personal data” in certain jurisdictions, including the European Union (“EU”), such as:

  * _Transaction Data,_ which includes details about payments.
  * _Technical Data,_ which includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data.
  * _Profile Data,_ which ** ** includes ** ** your username and password, information about your past purchases, loyalty rewards account information.
  * _Usage Data,_ which includes information about how you use our web site and services.
  * _Marketing and Communications Data,_ which ** ** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us

IF YOU ARE SITUATED IN THE EU, PLEASE SEE THE SECTION “ADDITIONAL EU DISCLOSURES” THAT PERTAIN TO OUR COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND ADDITIONAL RIGHTS YOU HAVE UNDER APPLICABLE LAW.

**Non-Personal Information:**

As noted above, we may collect information that is not Personal Information (“Non-Personal Information”).  We may aggregate Personal Information so that the aggregated information does not personally identify you or anyone else, such as by using Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our customers who live in a particular area ("Aggregate Information").  Because Non-Personal Information does not personally identify you, we may collect, use and disclose Non-Personal Information for any purpose permitted by law and subject to the section titled “Additional EU Disclosures”.  In some instances, we may combine Non-Personal Information with Personal Information.  If we combine any Non-Personal Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information.

**Information Usage and Disclosure:**

Besides using your Personal Information ourselves, we may send your Personal Information to other companies, affiliates and third parties to help us process your Personal Information for the purposes set out in this policy.

We use Personal Information and other information as described herein:

  * to process and fulfill any orders that you have placed,
  * to contact you about our products and services and provide you with our products and services,
  * to personalize your experience with us including by presenting products or offers tailored to you,
  * to allow you to use, communicate and interact with others on our Web site,
  * to administer our loyalty rewards program,
  * to respond to your direct inquiries,
  * to add you to our mailing lists and send you emails from time to time.  

We may also share your information with third parties such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, infrastructure provision, information technology services, customer service, e-mail delivery services, credit card processing, auditing, training, and other similar services.  These third parties may have access to Personal Information necessary to perform their functions.  One such third party is Shopify, provider of our online storefront platform. To see how Shopify will use your personally identifying information, please review their privacy policy here. To view their Terms of Use, [click here.](https://www.shopify.com/legal/terms)

We will not sell your Personal Information to any third party not affiliated with theBalm without your consent except in connection with the sale or merger of theBalm or the division responsible for such services.  

Additionally, we may disclose Personal Information and other information as we believe necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain; and (h) for legitimate business interests. 

We may use Aggregate Information and Non-Personal Information to improve and enhance your experience on the Web site and for our market research activities. For example, and subject to section titled “Additional EU Disclosures”, we may share Aggregate Information and Non-Personal Information with unaffiliated third parties, such as business partners, manufacturers, distributors and retailers, in a form in which means the shared information will not contain nor be linked to any Personal Information.   

Please note that if you specifically consent to additional uses of your Personal Information, we may use your Personal Information in a manner consistent with that consent. Finally, we reserve the right to supplement your Personal Information with information we gather from other sources which may include information we gather from online and offline sources.

**Interest Based Advertising:**

We may ourselves, or with third party vendors, use information we collect or vendor information to deliver targeted advertising to you when you visit other websites or our Web site. Cookies, clickstream data, and other similar technologies described below may be used in this process. For example, if you are searching for information on a particular product, we or our vendor may cause an advertisement to appear on other websites you view with information on that product. This form of advertising, sometimes called “behavioral advertising,” which enables us and our vendors to know your interests in connection with the delivery of that specific ad. We believe that such advertising is helpful because you will see advertisements that are relevant to your interests. However, if you would like to opt out of these interest-based advertisements, please follow the opt-out process described below under “Opt-Out.”

__Cookies and Similar Technology:__

We may store some information on your device or device hardrive as a cookie or similar type of file (such as clear gifs, web beacons, tags, and similar technologies that work on mobile devices) to collect data related to usage of the Web site. "Cookies" are pieces of information that may be placed on your computer by a web site for the purpose of collecting data to facilitate and enhance your communication and interaction with that web site.   Such data may include, without limitation, the address of the websites you visited before and after you visited the Web site, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, what pages in the Web site you visit and what links you clicked on, the region where your device is located, and geo-IP data.We may use cookies to customize your visit to the Web site and for other purposes to make your visit more convenient or to enable us to enhance our service.   We do not use cookies to retrieve Personal Information from your computer for purposes that are unrelated to the Web site or your interaction with the Web site. In addition to the tracking technologies described below under “Site Analytics”, we also use the following cookies, tags and trackers:

COOKIE

| 

DURATION/TYPE

| 

PURPOSE

| 

MORE INFORMATION  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

Persistent, first party

| 

Google Analytics collects information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect certain information, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Click here for more information on Google Analytics: [_https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245_](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)   
  
DoubleClick

| 

Persistent, session and third party

| 

DoubleClick provides information about visitors, such as the websites they visit before and/or after visiting a website

| 

Click here for more information about DoubleClick: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>   
  
Facebook Custom Audience

| 

Persistent, session and third party

| 

Facebook uses a business's CRM data to match it to people in their database to create a custom audience for advertising campaigns.

| 

Click here for more information on Facebook connect: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other  
  
Yotpo

| 

Persistent, session and third party

| 

Yotpo collects an order ID, amount, and currency and sends the data to Yotpo (with or without the cookie which contains extra information) upon checkout.

| 

Click here for more information on Yotpo:  https://www.yotpo.com/privacy-policy/  
  
Facebook Connect

| 

Persistent, session and third party

| 

When a user chooses to access a third-party website through Facebook Connect, they allow that website to retrieve information they have given to Facebook, including their full name, pictures wall posts, friend information, etc. This not only allows the user to skip the basic registration steps required by most websites, but it also allows the website to update the user's Facebook wall and news feed with their activities. By gaining access to the user's friends list, the website is able to show the user which of their friends have also accessed the website through Facebook Connect.

| 

Click here for more information on Facebook connect: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other  
  
Sweet Tooth (Smile.io)

| 

Persistent, session and third party

| 

When you install Sweet Tooth (Smile.io) you grant permission to Shopify or BigCommerce to share customer and order data to Smile.io through APIs. When you use Smile.io to run your loyalty program or other features, we will collect data about your customers such as their reward redemption activities.

| 

Click here for more information on Sweet Tooth: <https://smile.io/privacy-policy>  
  
__Clickstream:__

As you use the Internet, a trail of electronic information is left at each web site you visit.  This information, which is sometimes referred to as "clickstream data," can be collected and stored by a web site's server.  Clickstream data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the web site from which you linked to the Web site.  We may collect and use clickstream data as a form of Aggregate Information to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of our Web site, how visitors navigate throughout the Web site and how we may tailor our web pages to better meet the needs of visitors.  This information will be used to improve our Web site and our services. Any collection or use of clickstream data will be anonymous and aggregate, and will not intentionally contain any Personal Information.

__Site Analytics:__

We may work with third-party service providers who use the technologies described in this section to conduct website analytics to help us track and understand how visitors use our Web site.  One such provider is Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyze how users use the Web site. The information generated by the cookie about your use (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Web site, compiling reports on activity for its staff and providing other services relating to web page activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. By using the Web site and accepting cookies, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Please refer to the Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web, found at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Interactive Tools on our Web site:**

Certain features on our Web site may give you an opportunity to interact with us and others.  These may include blogs, message boards, messaging functionality, chat functionality, and creating community profiles.  When you use these features you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name and e-mail address, may be publicly available to others.  We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit through these interactive features and we strongly discourage you from disclosing any sensitive Personal Information (such as health or credit card information) through these features.  If you use these features, your Personal Information may remain on the Web site even after you cease use of the Web site.

**Security:**

The security of your Personal Information is very important to us.  We attempt to provide for the secure transmission of your information from your computer to our servers by utilizing encryption software. However, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and theBalm, or information stored on the Web site or our servers, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties such as hackers and your use of the Web site demonstrates your assumption of this risk. We have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect.  Only those employees who need access to your information in order to perform their duties are authorized to have access to your Personal Information.  If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with the Contact section below.

**Data Retention:**

We will retain your information for as long as your account or inquiry is active or as needed to provide you with the Web site and for a reasonable time thereafter in accordance with our standard procedures or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements. Even if we delete some or all of your Personal Information, we may continue to retain and use anonymous or aggregated data previously collected. Please note that we will not be liable for disclosures of your data due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties.

**Protection for Children**

Our Web site is intended for ages 18 and over. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children.  When we become aware that Personal Information (or other information that is protected under applicable law) from a child under 13 (or such other age as may be restricted under local law) has been collected, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

**Other Web sites and Social Networking Services:**

Our Web site may contain links to other web sites not maintained by theBalm. Other web sites may also reference or link to our Web site.  The inclusion of a link on the Web site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites operated by third parties that are linked to or integrated with our Web site, or for the privacy practices of third party Internet advertising companies.  We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Web site, or surf the Internet, and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that you visit.

Our Web site may allow you to engage with social media services, such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram (“Social Networks”), and widgets such as the social media icon buttons, or interactive mini-programs that run on our Web site or which link from Social Networks to our Web site (“Social Functions”). These Social Functions may access, collect and integrate with your Social Network accounts and information. For example, these Social Functions may collect your IP address, identify which page you are visiting on our Web site, or set a cookie. Social Functions may also be used to register you as a Web site user.  For example, if you are not currently registered as a Web site user and you use certain Social Functions, you will be asked to enter your Social Network credentials and then be given the option to register and join the Web site. If you choose to use these Social Functions, you may be sharing certain Social Network profile elements with us, including your name, birthday (month/day), comments, contacts, email address, photos or favorite teams. This sharing is subject to each Social Network’s own privacy policy and terms of use. We do not control those Social Networks or your profiles on those services. Nor do we modify your privacy settings on those services or establish rules about how your personal information on those services will be used.  Social Functions are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Web site. Your interactions with them are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them. Please refer to the privacy settings in your Social Network account to manage the data that is shared with us through your account. Information you include and transmit online in a publicly accessible blog, chat room or Social Network, or that you share in an open forum such as an in-person panel or survey, may be viewed and used by others without any restrictions. We do not control such uses of your personal information, and by using such services you assume the risk and acknowledge that the personal information provided by you may be viewed and used by us and/or third parties for any number of purposes and that the usage restrictions set forth in this Privacy Policy do not apply to such services. To request removal of your personal information from a blog, community forum or other publicly-accessible part of the Web site, contact us at privacy@thebalm.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so.

The Web site may integrate with social networking services.  You understand that we do not control such services and are not liable for the manner in which they operate.  While we may provide you with the ability to use such services in connection with our Web site, we are doing so merely as an accommodation and, like you, are relying upon those third party services to operate properly and fairly.

**Opt-Out:**

To opt-out of any future promotional messages from us, you should send an unsubscribe request to us at [info@thebalm.com](mailto:info@thebalm.com). We will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt.  Please note that if you opt out in this manner, certain aspects of the Web site may no longer be available to you.

The online advertising industry provides a service through which you may opt-out of receiving targeted ads from certain data partners and other advertising partners that participate in self-regulatory programs.  We comply with the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising set forth by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) and the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (“EDAA”). You can opt-out of targeted advertising from certain providers at [www.aboutads.info/consumers](http://www.aboutads.info/consumers). Please note that by opting out, you will continue to see generic advertising that is not tailored to your specific interests and activities. To be clear, cookie-based opt-outs must be performed on each device and browser that you wish to have opted-out. For example, if you have opted out on your device browser, that opt-out will not be effective on your mobile device. You must separately opt out on each device. EU residents who have provided their consent to our use of cookies and similar technologies can use the EDAA’s opt out tool which can be found at <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. 

If you want to stop or restrict the placement of cookies or flush any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, please refer to and adjust your web browser preferences. Further information on cookies is available at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). By deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our Web site or some of its functionality may be affected. Cookies and similar items are not used by us to automatically retrieve Personal Information from your device without your knowledge.

Please note that we do not respond to or honor “do not track” (a/k/a/ DNT) signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers.

**Changes to policy:**

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. Your continued use of the Web site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes.

**Communications with theBalm:**

By providing your email address to us, you expressly consent to receive emails from us.  We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send information about other products or services developed or provided by us or by other third party manufacturers, services and/or distributors that we believe will be of interest to its audience.  If you receive an unwanted email from us, you can simply reply and ask not to receive future emails.  We also give you the option to remove your Personal Information (and other information required by law) from our list of active users completely.  All unsubscribe or opt-out requests should be sent to us at [info@thebalm.com](mailto:info@thebalm.com) and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt.  We are not responsible for removing your information from the lists of any third party who has been provided your information in accordance with this policy, such as a business partner.

**California Privacy:  **

Under California Law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of Personal Information, such as name, email address and mailing address and the type of services provided to the customer that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes and (b) the names and addresses of all such third parties. To request the above information, please contact us by email at privacy@thebalm.com. If you do not want your Personal Information shared with any third party who may use such information for direct marketing purposes, then you may opt out of such disclosures by sending an email to us at privacy@thebalm.com. 

**Additional EU Disclosures:**

_Legal Basis:_

We will only use your personal data as defined by the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where you have consented to a certain use of your personal data.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

To the extent permitted under applicable laws, we will also process, transfer, disclose and preserve personal data when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary.

_Data controller:_

Shipman Associates, LLC d/b/a theBalm cosmetics Is the data controller of all personal data collected through our Web site. To contact us, please see the section titled “Contact Us”.

If you are situated in the EU and have any complaints regarding our privacy practices, you have the right to make a complaint at any time to your local Supervisory Authority. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach your Supervisory Authority so please contact us in the first instance. If you have a complaint, please contact our EU privacy manager located in Slovenia at: privacy@thebalm.com.

_Provision of personal data and_ _failure to provide personal data:_

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with our services). In this case, we will not be able to provide services to you.

_Third parties or publicly available sources._ _ _ We may receive personal data about you from various third parties such as Social Networks (as described above) and Shopify to assist us with your sale and refund procedures.

_Withdrawing your consent:_

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at privacy@thebalm.com.

_Data Transfer:_

We may transfer personal data from the EU to the USA and other countries, some of which have not been determined by the European Commission to have an adequate level of data protection. If we transfer personal data outside the EU to a processor, such transfer will be in compliance with the requirements of the GDPR.

_Use of your personal data for marketing purposes:_

 We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising:

  * Promotional offers from us: We may use your personal data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or used our services and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
  * Third-party marketing: We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside our company for their marketing purposes.

To see how you can opt out of marketing communications, please see the section titled “Opt-Out”.

_Data Subject Rights:_

If you are a situated in the EU, under the GDPR as a data subject you have the following rights:

  * _Right to access_ – This right allows individuals to obtain confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him or her is being process and provide access to such personal data. It also allows individuals to request details of the processing of his or her Personal Information, including, without limitation, categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or will be disclosed and purposes of processing.
  * _Right to rectify_ – This right allows individuals to rectify any inaccurate personal data about him or her.
  * _Right to restrict processing_ – This right allows individuals to block or suppress processing of personal data under certain circumstances.
  * _Right to be forgotten_ – This right is also known as the “right to erasure”. It is an individual’s right to have personal data erased or to prevent processing in specific circumstances.
  * _Right of data portability_ – This right allows individuals to move, copy or transfer personal data from one place to another in a secure manner without interrupting the integrity and usability of the information.
  * _Right to object to processing_ – This right allows individuals to object to certain types of processing, including direct marketing, profiling and providing for purposes of scientific or historical research and statistics.

To exercise your rights under the GDPR, please contact us at [privacy@thebalm.com](mailto:privacy@thebalm.com). Please note that in order for you to assert these rights, we may need to verify your identity to confirm your right to access your personal data.  This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. In order to verify your identity, we may need to gather more personal data from you than we currently have.

**Web site Terms and Conditions:**

Use of this Web site is governed by, and subject to, the legal notices contained at _“Term and Conditions”_. Your use, or access, of the Web site constitutes your agreement to be bound by these provisions.

**Contact:**

For questions or concerns relating to privacy, we can be contacted at: [privacy@thebalm.com](mailto:privacy@thebalm.com). If you are situation in the EU and have any complaints regarding our privacy practices, you have the right to complain to a supervisory authority.

**Site Maintenance:**

Our Web site is maintained in the United States of America. Subject to the subsection “Data Transfer” in the section titled “Additional EU Disclosures”, by using the Web site, you authorize the export of your information to the USA and its storage and use as specified in this policy.
